- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
♪ ♪
narrator:
Ladies and gentlemen,
叙述者：
女士们、先生们，
boys and girls,
welcome
男孩和女孩，
欢迎
to the most fascinating place
on Earth
到最迷人的地方
在地球上
Bubbletown!
泡泡城！
A bouncing, vibrant city,
一座充满活力、充满活力的城市，
where everyone...
每个人都...
[bubble ducks quacking]
and everything
[泡泡鸭嘎嘎叫]
和一切
is comprised entirely
完全由
of globules of air!
空气小球！
- Ooh!
- 哦！
A whole city made of bubbles!
整个城市都是由泡泡组成的！
I'm so excited!
我太激动了！
narrator: Let's take
a closer look
旁白：我们来吧
仔细看看
at this effervescent city!
在这座充满活力的城市！
Some bubbletowners drive
to work in their bubble cars.
一些泡泡镇居民开车
在他们的泡泡车里工作。
While others simply float.
而其他人只是漂浮。
Having a bubble car is great
because parking is a cinch!
拥有一辆泡泡车真是太好了
因为停车是小菜一碟！
Bubbletown also provides
泡泡城还提供
excellent
public transportation.
优秀的
公共交通。
Seats are always available
座位随时有空
because these high-tech buses
can account
因为这些高科技巴士
可以记账
for any number
of passengers.
对于任何数字
的乘客。
Here are some workers
going to work
这里有一些工人
去上班
in their bubble building.
在他们的泡沫建筑中。
- Hah!
- 哈！
[straining]
[紧张]
Oof!
narrator: [laughs]
钱币！
旁白：[笑]
You may wanna
use the door.
你可能想要
使用门。
This office uses
stand-up desks,
该办公室使用
站立式办公桌，
and the ceiling
和天花板
for a more efficient
work environment.
为了更高效
工作环境。
- Whoa, whoa-whoa.
- 哇哦，哇哦。
Wow!
哇！
[laughs]
[笑]
narrator: Yes, there's
all kinds of things
旁白：是的，有
各种各样的事情
to see and do in Bubbletown!
泡泡城的景点和活动！
[jazzy music playing]
[爵士乐演奏]
You can enjoy Bubbletown's
您可以享受泡泡城的乐趣
very own Bubble Band!
非常有自己的泡泡带！
- Oh, yeah!
- 哦，是的！
[scatting]
[分散]
[stomach rumbling]
[肚子咕咕叫]
narrator:
And if you're hungry,
叙述者：
如果你饿了，
why not try a bubble dog
为什么不试试泡泡狗呢
from one of our many
bubble food vendors?
来自我们众多之一
泡泡食品摊贩？
- One, please.
- 请来一张。
- Here you are.
- 给你。
- Mmm!
- 嗯！
[burps loudly]
Oh, yeah!
[大声打嗝]
哦，是啊！
I am rabid for these dogs!
我对这些狗很狂热！
[laughs]
Huh?
[笑]
啊？
Hey, it's my old pal,
Bubble Buddy!
嘿，这是我的老朋友，
泡泡哥！
Hiya, Bubble Buddy!
嗨，泡泡伙伴！
- SpongeBob?
- 海绵宝宝？
- Gee, it's good to see ya!
- Whoa! [groans]
- 哎呀，很高兴见到你！
- 哇！ [呻吟]
- Uh, oops.
Sorry.
- 呃，哎呀。
对不起。
- Oh, don't worry about it.
-哦，别担心。
- So how you been?
How are things?
- 那你过得怎么样？
最近怎么样？
- Oh. Not so good,
SpongeBob.
- 哦。不太好，
海绵宝宝。
On my way into town
在我进城的路上
I got a flat tire
on my motor scooter.
我的轮胎漏气了
在我的摩托车上。
[downtrodden music]
[压抑的音乐]
- Let me see if I can fix
that for you.
- 让我看看是否可以修复
给你的。
[mellow music]
[柔和的音乐]
♪ ♪
[inhales, exhales
energetically]
[吸气，呼气
精力充沛]
[engine revving]
[rock music]
[发动机转速]
[摇滚乐]
Ta-da!
哒哒！
- All right!
- 好的！
- Say, that was
some pretty handy
- 说，那是
一些非常方便
bubble work you did there, son.
儿子，你在那里做了泡泡工作。
- Why, SpongeBob is
the best bubble blower I know.
- 为什么，海绵宝宝是
我所知道的最好的吹泡泡器。
He can inflate
and create anything!
他可以充气
并创造任何东西！
- You don't say?
Hey, can you help me?
- 你不说？
嘿，你能帮我吗？
I've got a small leak
in my roof.
我有一个小泄漏
在我的屋顶上。
[thunder rumbles]
[雷声隆隆]
- Honey!
[screams]
- 蜂蜜！
[尖叫声]
- I can help you?
- 我可以帮你？
By blowing bubbles?
通过吹泡泡？
Oh...[sighing]
哦...[叹气]
- And...clear!
- 而且……清楚！
- Count me in!
- 算我一个吧！
- Fantastic!
- 极好的！
- Say, when you're
done helping him,
- 说，当你
帮他做完了，
my house could use
a new rec room!
我的房子可以用
一个新的娱乐室！
- I need some pajamas.
- 我需要一些睡衣。
- Okay, mm, uh-huh.
- 好的，嗯，嗯。
- I want another sandwich!
- 我想要另一个三明治！
- Monster truck tires!
- 怪物卡车轮胎！
- Never fear,
people of Bubbletown!
- 永远不要害怕，
泡泡镇的人们！
I'm on it!
我正在做！
[dramatic Western music]
[戏剧性的西方音乐]
♪ ♪
[inhaling, exhales]
[吸气，呼气]
- Wow.
Thanks, SpongeBob!
- 哇。
谢谢，海绵宝宝！
- All right!
- 好的！
[engine revving, tires screech]
[发动机加速，轮胎尖叫]
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
[laughs]
[tires screech]
[笑]
[轮胎尖叫声]
[light music]
[轻音乐]
♪ ♪
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Oh, Bubble Buddy, this has been
the best day of my life!
哦，泡泡伙伴，这已经是
我一生中最美好的一天！
I love it here
in Bubbletown!
我喜欢这里
在泡泡镇！
[cheering, laughing]
[欢呼、大笑]
- Watch out for those--
- 小心那些--
[clattering]
[咔哒声]
- Excuse me, sir,
- 对不起，先生，
but you seem to have
stepped in my dogs.
但你似乎有
踏入我的狗。
[bubble dogs whimpering]
[泡泡狗呜咽]
- Oh, uh-uh, pardon me, ma'am.
Let me just--
- 哦，呃呃，请原谅，女士。
让我——
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- Oh.
- 哦。
Whoa! Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
哇！哇、哇、哇、哇！
Whoa!
[wailing]
哇！
[哀号]
My eyes!
我的眼睛！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- SpongeBob, come back!
- 海绵宝宝，回来吧！
- Amy, will you marry me?
- 艾米，你愿意嫁给我吗？
- Yes! I will!
- 是的！我会！
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- Aw.
- 噢。
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
[bubble ducks quacking]
[泡泡鸭嘎嘎叫]
[wailing]
[哀号]
[loud popping]
[爆裂声]
[screaming]
[popping]
[尖叫]
[爆裂声]
- I now dedicate
this new school
- 我现在奉献
这所新学校
for overly cute children.
对于过于可爱的孩子。
[crowd cheering]
- I "wuv" to learn!
[人群欢呼]
- 我“wuv”来学习！
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
[triumphant music playing]
[胜利的音乐演奏]
- [screaming]
- [尖叫]
- Hey! That was my job!
- 嘿！那是我的工作！
- I'm so sorry!
I can't stop!
- 我很抱歉！
我停不下来！
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[all gasp]
[全都喘气]
[slowly] Watch out!
[慢慢地]小心！
[wailing, screaming]
[哀号、尖叫]
[explosion]
[爆炸]
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
[groans]
[呻吟]
[weeping]
[哭泣]
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
Oh, thank goodness,
you're okay.
哦，谢天谢地，
你没事吧。
- No!
Stay away!
- 不！
远离！
[screaming]
I'm a monster!
[尖叫]
我是一个怪物！
[whimpering] A monster!
[呜咽]怪物！
- [gasps]
- Just look at the destruction
- [喘气]
- 看看破坏情况
I hath wrought!
我已经做到了！
[all groaning, wailing]
[所有人呻吟、哀号]
- My bubble legs!
- 我的泡泡腿！
- My monster truck tires!
- 我的怪物卡车轮胎！
- Okay, that doesn't
look great.
- 好吧，那不是
看起来很棒。
[uneasy chuckle]
But I'm sure
[不安的笑声]
但我确信
we can get it all sorted out.
我们可以把一切都解决掉。
[sirens wailing]
[both gasp]
[警笛哀嚎]
[两人都喘气]
[funky music]
[时髦音乐]
- I'm afraid
the only sorting out
- 我害怕
唯一的整理
your friend's going
to be doing
你的朋友要去
正在做
is in jail.
在监狱里。
For popping a large portion
of the city.
用于爆开大部分
城市的。
- Okay, take me away!
- 好吧，带我走吧！
I'm guilty!
我有罪！
I deserve whatever punishment
you give me.
无论什么惩罚我都应得
你给我。
[daunting music]
[令人畏惧的音乐]
- All right,
you get one phone call.
- 好吧，
你接到一个电话。
- Okay.
- 好的。
[line trills, recorded voice]
The machine, hold on.
[台词颤音，录音]
机器，等一下。
Gotta leave a message.
One second.
一定要留言啊
一秒钟。
[beep]
Hey, Mr. Krabs.
[嘟嘟声]
嘿，蟹老板。
It's me, SpongeBob.
是我，海绵宝宝。
Um, I'm in jail.
In Bubbletown.
嗯，我在监狱里。
在泡泡镇。
They gave me
three life sentences, so um...
他们给了我
三个无期徒刑，所以嗯...
so um...
[sniffles]
所以嗯...
[抽鼻子]
I might be late
for my next shift.
我可能会迟到
为我的下一个轮班。
I'm so sorry!
我很抱歉！
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
- Later...
- 之后...
[tropical music]
[热带音乐]
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- Mr. Squidward!
- 章鱼哥先生！
- Huh, hah, what, who?
- 哈哈哈，什么，谁？
- What's going on here?
- 这是怎么回事？
How long have these folks
been waiting
这些人多久了
一直在等待
to give me their money?
把他们的钱给我？
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[straining]
[紧张]
I'm okay!
我没事！
- Well...?
- 出色地...？
- What's the point?
There's no one in the kitchen
- 有什么意义？
厨房里没人
to make any food.
制作任何食物。
- Hm? Hm, huh, eh, ah.
- 嗯？嗯嗯嗯嗯。
[high-pitched] What!
Where's SpongeBob?
[高声调]什么！
海绵宝宝在哪里？
Didn't he call in?
他没打电话过来吗？
- Hey Mr. Krabs,
it's me, SpongeBob.
- 嘿，蟹老板，
是我，海绵宝宝。
Um, I'm in jail.
嗯，我在监狱里。
In Bubbletown.
They gave me--
在泡泡镇。
他们给了我——
- Oh, barnacles.
- 哦，藤壶。
Me fry cook's in the clink.
我用叮叮当当的方式炒厨师。
You have the conn,
Mr. Squidward.
你有连接，
章鱼哥先生。
I'll be back as soon
as I can!
我会尽快回来
尽我所能！
- Wha--
- Whoa.
- 什--
- 哇哦。
[dreadful music]
[可怕的音乐]
- [straining]
- [紧张]
[stealthy jazz music]
[隐秘的爵士乐]
[cheering]
[欢呼]
- [laughing]
- [笑]
- Mr. Krabs!
- [grunts]
- 蟹老板！
- [咕哝]
This is a prison break, boy-o.
Let's get a move on!
这是越狱，男孩。
让我们继续前进吧！
We've got a bunch
of hungry customers back home,
我们有一堆
饥饿的顾客回到家，
and I need your help fleecing--
我需要你的帮助来诈骗——
I mean, I mean
feeding them!
我是说，我是说
喂他们！
- Oh, I'm sorry, Mr. Krabs.
I can't go.
- 哦，对不起，蟹老板。
我不能去。
I haven't finished paying
my debt to society yet.
我还没付完钱
我对社会的亏欠还没有。
- [stammering]
Can't go?
- [结巴]
不能去吗？
When I say we're leaving,
当我说我们要离开时
we're leaving!
我们要走了！
- Hey! You're not supposed
to be in here!
- 嘿！你不应该
来到这里！
- Eat claw, bubble cop!
- 吃爪子吧，泡泡警察！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
- Uh--huh?
- 呃-嗯？
[gasps, screams]
[喘气，尖叫]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Honey!
- 蜂蜜！
[claw propellers whirring]
[爪形螺旋桨呼呼作响]
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
[bubble ducks quacking]
[泡泡鸭嘎嘎叫]
- [sighing]
- [叹气]
Good thing they were
all just bubbles, eh?
还好他们是
一切都只是泡沫，是吗？
Okay, let's get out of here.
好吧，我们离开这里吧。
Uh-oh.
呃哦。
- You popped it all.
- 你把它全部弹出了。
There's nothing left.
什么都没有剩下了。
- Forget it, SpongeBob.
- 算了，海绵宝宝。
It's Bubbletown.
这是泡泡镇。
- No!
I can't forget it.
- 不！
我无法忘记它。
Just leave me here, Mr. Krabs.
蟹老板，把我留在这里吧。
My tears will be
a fitting memorial
我的泪水将会
一个合适的纪念馆
to the bubble city
that I loved.
到泡泡城
我所爱的。
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- So sorry to interrupt,
but I might have a solution
- 很抱歉打扰，
但我可能有一个解决方案
that works for everyone!
这对每个人都有效！
- [gasps]
Oh, yeah!
- [喘气]
哦，是啊！
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Let's blow
this popsicle stand.
- 让我们吹吧
这个冰棍架
[laughs]
[笑]
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
[chattering, laughing]
[闲聊、大笑]
- I can't believe
how quickly you inflated
- 我不敢相信
你充气的速度有多快
the whole city again,
SpongeBob!
整个城市再次
海绵宝宝！
- Yep! The whole city.
- 是的！整个城市。
Plus this new Krusty Krab.
再加上这个新的蟹堡王。
- [laughing] Yeah.
- [笑] 是的。
Franchisin's a great idea,
boy-o!
特许经营是个好主意
男孩哦！
I am making money
claw over fist here.
我正在赚钱
这里用爪子捂住拳头。
Hey, what's the exchange rate
for bubbles to real money?
你好，汇率是多少
为了泡沫到真金白银？
- There is none!
- 没有！
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
[all laugh]
[全都笑]
- Exchange rate?
- 汇率？
[laughing]
[笑]
- That's it.
We're done here.
- 就是这样。
我们到这里就完成了。
[loud pop]
[爆裂声]
- Huh.
[giggles]
- 嗯。
[咯咯笑]
[bubble ducks quacking]
[泡泡鸭嘎嘎叫]
- I "wuv" to learn!
- 我“wuv”来学习！